我真的很喜欢这些新的Pixel手机
So I really like these new Pixel phones.
今年的新设计显而易见 还有新的规格和功能
New designs this year, obviously, but also new specs, new features,
还有一些新问题 当然 还有新的价格
also new issues, but of course, new price tags.
我们真的要深入挖掘一下这些手机
So we really got to jump into the nitty gritty
的实际优点
of what's actually good about them.
所以 我们期待真正强大的旗舰手机
So we've been hoping for a real complete flagship quality competitor
来自谷歌
from Google
已经有一段时间了
for a while now.
一方面
And on one hand
感觉我们终于迎来了这些手机
it feels like we finally got them.
但另一方面
But on the other hand
你们有没有看过谷歌发布这些手机的活动？
did you guys watch the Google event announcing these things?
通过发布会能看出公司对产品的真实看法
I feel like you can learn a lot about how a company really feels
关于他们正在展示的产品内容
about the products that they're presenting
通过观看发布活动内容
by just watching the announcement event.
而这些更像是软件展示
And these felt like a software showcase
只是顺便有了几款手机
that just also happened to have some phones to go with it
我想这也算不上什么奇怪的事
which I guess is not insane
考虑到Nexus和Pixel的历史
when you know the history of Nexus and Pixel
这让我对这些手机产生了反感
but it did the opposite of give me confidence in these phones.
不过现在我已经连续用这些手机两周了
But now I've been using these phones for two weeks straight
我觉得我能告诉你这些手机的优缺点
and I actually feel like I can tell you what's good or bad about them.
所以我主要想说的是硬件
So hardware is mostly what I'm talking about
我觉得这些手机确实像旗舰机 给人好印象
when I say these phones feel like flagships in a good way.
容易把它们看成和去年一样
Like it would be easy to dismiss them as almost the same as last year,
只是变得方了一点
just squared up.
但还有很多其他的小事情
But there are a lot of other little things too.
比如屏幕最大亮度更亮
Like the screens are brighter at their max brightness,
Pixel 9达到2700尼特
2700 nits for the Pixel 9
而9 Pro的亮度则是3000尼特
and 3000 nits for the 9 Pros.
还有四周的边框也很均匀
And then the even bezels all the way around.
这需要更多的思考
That requires some extra consideration,
让OLED面板的边缘包裹
wrapping the edges of the OLED panels
在角落处
under those corners.
所有机型上都有新的超声波指纹识别器
And there's a new ultrasonic fingerprint reader under here on all of them.
最后 它的速度大幅提升
Finally, it's way faster
和可靠性都远超之前差劲的光学识别器
and more reliable than the disappointing optical ones from before
我唯一想要的不过是这件小事
the only thing I wish it's such a small thing
我希望能随时解锁
But I wish I could just unlock at any time
现在显示屏完全关闭时 你必须保持
when the display is completely off like currently you have to have the
始终显示状态
always-on display on
要么按电源按钮 要么收到通知
or Hit the power button or be getting a notification
你只需轻按即可解锁 就像三星手机那样
and then you can unlock with a quick touch but Like on Samsung phones
显示屏上的那个点始终是热点
that spot on the display is always a hotspot no matter what.
你只需触摸那里解锁
You can just unlock by touching there.
我希望Pixel在黑屏时也能如此
So I kind of wish the Pixel would let me do that from a blank screen too.
触觉反馈非常出色
The haptics are really nice again
而且今年按钮的手感很棒
and the buttons are really clicky this year.
当然 硬件的表现也是非常重要的
But then of course the hardware is what's on the inside too.
这就是全新的Tensor G4芯片
So that is the new Tensor G4 chip
还有不少额外的内存
and a bunch of extra RAM.
其实 Tensor G4 的性能并没有比
Now, the Tensor G4 isn't actually that much more powerful
去年的芯片强多少
than last year's chip.
其实 你几乎不会察觉到有什么不同
In fact, you probably won't notice a difference
对于你在手机上进行的99%的操作来说
for 99% of the stuff you do on the phone.
不过 真正重要的是一个全新的NPU 它更强大
But what's actually significant is a new NPU that's way more powerful
专注于AI任务
and dedicated to AI tasks.
而且更多的RAM同样专门用于AI任务
And the way more RAM is also dedicated to AI tasks.
我听说大部分RAM实际上是专门预留给AI相关的任务
I'm told a big portion of the RAM is literally reserved for AI stuff.
我很快会讲到这些AI的内容 请放心
So I will get to all that AI stuff in a minute, don't worry.
不过 考虑到我们所处的时代
But just in the world that we're living in,
很多主要新智能手机的市场动态在这里
where the meta for a lot of these major new smartphones is,
嗯 有一些微小的改进
okay, minor new improvements here and there,
但主要还是加入了不少新的人工智能功能
but mainly just a bunch of new AI features
以及各种新功能
and capabilities.
我很高兴Pixel的硬件设计也
I'm glad that the Pixel also got a bunch of meaningful feeling
很有深意
hardware stuff too.
显然 没错
And then obviously, yes
这个手机的边框确实是方方正正的
you do have the squared off sides that I just know
这正好和世界上的iPhone、三星等手机相匹配
are supposed to fit in with the iPhones and Samsungs of the world.
我之前提到过
I've said it before
我喜欢它的造型和触感
I like the look and feel.
这同样适用于这个新的相机罩
And that also applies to this new camera visor
这看起来不太像面罩 反而更像个架子
which is less of a visor
我想它更像一个架子 再加上面罩的功能
and I guess more of like a shelf visor.
在一些渲染中 岛的样子看起来有点奇怪
Island now kind of looks a bit weird in some renders
不过你得相信我 亲自看过的人都会觉得不错
but you just kind of have to trust me seeing it in person
这个真是太棒了！
It's fire.
我很喜欢 尽管它可能会
I like it Even if it will
如果和去年一样 它肯定会在角落里积满灰尘
totally collect dust in just the same way as last year in the corners.
这个真的不错
It's nice
现在有个新尺寸 适合想要专业手机的
Oh, and I almost forgot there is a new size so you can have a pro phone
而且它不是XL 我非常喜欢这个选择！
but without it being an XL Love the choice.
我有点儿担心
I am a little worried
那个可能不如两个极端的型号卖得好
that that one is probably won't sell as well as the two extremes
不过我只是想说
but I'm just
我很高兴今年我们有更多选择
I'm glad we have the choice this year.
趁它还在的时候要好好珍惜
Be happy about it before it gets discontinued.
总的来说 这听起来不错
So anyway, it all sounds pretty good
不过我还是有些不满
but I do have a few gripes
我觉得这是合情合理的
which I'm allowed to
它的价格是1000美元
it's $1,000.
所以电池的大小和去年差不多
So the size of the batteries is about the same as last year,
小型号的电池容量大约是4700毫安时
4,700 milliamp hours in the smaller size ones,
大手机的电池容量大约是5000毫安时
5,000 milliamp hours in the big phone.
我在使用XL时 电池续航一直表现不错
I've had pretty good battery life
与XL一起使用的电池续航表现较差
like a minus battery life with the XL consistently
屏幕亮度高的情况下 使用时间超过五小时
five plus hours of screen on time lots of heavy high brightness use
不过 它们充电速度仍然不快
but they still don't charge that fast
XL的最大充电功率大约是37瓦特
like the XL is maxing out at like 37 watts.
而且在小型号的手机上 充电速度实际上更慢
And it's actually slightly slower on the smaller phones.
我不是说你必须使用那种‘真我320瓦特’的极快充电
Now I'm not saying you gotta go thermonuclear level
真我320瓦特极快充电
real me 320 watt fast charging
充电速度快得让人惊讶
light your phone on fire charging speeds or anything like that.
我只是想说 快速充电还是挺不错的
I'm just saying fast charging would be nice.
就50到60瓦 这样就好了
50, 60 watts, that's it.
我觉得这也没什么特别的
I feel like that's just not that insane
但是在使用手机方面会好很多
but would be significantly better for using the phone.
我还得提一下 Pixel 9的边框是哑光的 背面是光滑的
Now, I also need to say Pixel 9 has matte sides with glossy back
而Pixel 9 Pro的边框是光滑的 背面是哑光的
but the Pixel 9 Pro has glossy sides with the matte back.
这种设计我们以前见过
We've seen the strategy before.
我觉得哑光的边框外观更好看
I just think the matte sides look
而且手感也比光滑的要好得多
and feel so much better than the glossy
我有点希望能有哑光效果的手机外观
so I kind of wish you could get like a matte on matte look
不过这只是我个人的看法
but that's just me.
还有一件事
And then one more thing, of course
这些手机的起售价很高
these phones start at higher prices
或者基础版的起售价是799美元
or at least the base one starts at $799
不过这款手机要1000美元 128GB的存储起步
but this is a $1,000 phone that starts at 128 gigs of storage.
谢谢你 苹果
Thanks, Apple.
我想这也是现在的趋势了
I guess that's the standard now too
但是现在是2024年
but it's 2024.
我希望起步存储能是256GB
I would have liked, you know, 256 to start.
相机一直是谷歌手机体验中不可或缺的一部分
So cameras have always been a big part of the Google phone experience
至少最近一段时间是这样
or at least they have for a while now.
而在Pixel 9系列中
And on Pixel 9s
这个依然成立 但情况有所不同
that's still true, but not in exactly the same way.
总体而言
So all across the board
Pixel 9和9 Pro的主摄像头是相同的
the Pixel 9 and 9 Pro actually share the same primary camera
超广角镜头也是相同的
and the same ultra-wide.
Pro版则多了一个5倍变焦的长焦镜头
The Pros just get that extra telephoto, the 5x zoom
所有机型共享的主摄像头
And the primary camera that they all share
基本和去年一样
is basically the same as last year.
超广角镜头是全新设计
The ultra wide is new.
现在是48百万像素 而不是以前的12百万
It's 48 megapixels instead of 12
但最终分辨率降低到了12
but it bends down to 12.
来看看用这些新相机拍摄的效果吧
So look shooting with these new cameras.
效果非常不错！
It's great.
这是一款非常快速的手机相机应用
It's a quick smartphone camera app.
有许多简单易用的模式
There's a bunch of easy to use modes.
反应非常灵敏
It's responsive.
对焦速度很快
Focus is quick.
使用起来非常简单 表现也很稳定
It's easy, a consistent
能够快速处理出清晰的好照片
good pictures that process pretty quickly.
我对这些照片最深刻的印象是
What I mostly notice about these photos.
在我看来 它们看起来仍然处理得很夸张
is they still look very processed to me.
这就是目前几代 Pixel 手机的风格
Like this is the pixel look now these days with the last few generations.
这张照片有丰富的 HDR、高对比度
Just lots of HDR, lots of contrast,
和动态范围 同时也经过了较强的锐化处理
lots of dynamic range, also lots of sharpening.
这种效果没有我们在其他设备上看到的自然
It's just not as natural of a look as we've seen in some others.
这效果显得更加鲜明
It's just more on the punchy side
这对于在社交媒体上分享照片很好
which is honestly great for just sharing a photo on social media
但有些人可能更喜欢中性风格的照片
but some may prefer a more neutral photo.
Pro的新自拍相机在细节上
The new selfie camera on the Pro actually feels like
真的是最大的提升
the biggest improvement
在细节上
as far as detail
与普通Pixel 9相比 色彩更加丰富
and color over the regular Pixel 9
但它没有这一点
which doesn't get this.
不过我认为这款自拍相机非常不错
But I'd say this is a pretty nice selfie camera.
动态范围真是超广
Just so much dynamic range.
如果你想了解的话
But if you want to see
还可以听听Pixel拍摄的视频效果
and hear what video footage from the Pixel sounds like
我在Pixel 9 Pro XL的自动对焦频道上录制了一整段视频
I shot an entire video on the autofocus channel on the Pixel 9 Pro XL
在4K 30帧下
in 4K 30
完全没有外接硬件
with actually no external hardware.
我连麦克风都没插
I didn't even plug in a mic.
这就是设备自带的麦克风效果
This is just the built-in mics.
就我拿着手机
so yeah just me holding a phone
不放大根本看不出问题
if you don't zoom in at all the videos look great
清晰 但明显处理过头了
they're sharp but obviously still very processed.
你能看出来 它在优先处理图像分割
And you can see it like prioritizing segmentation
还有我脸上的灯光和颜色的变化
and like lighting on my face and shifting colors around.
我会在下面放个链接
So I'll leave a link below
如果你想看完整的eSprinter评测
if you want to watch that whole eSprinter review when it goes live.
顺便去那边订阅
And you might as well subscribe over there
其他汽车视频吧
while you're at it for other car videos.
不过这都是Pixel体验的一部分
But this is all part of the Pixel experience.
就像他们还在不断调试这些相机
Just like they're still tuning these cameras.
将来它们可能会显得更自然一些
They may end up looking a little more natural in the future
尽管已经过了一代人
even though it's been a generation.
这就是从这款手机中可以体验到的一项功能
Like that's one of the things that you can get out of this phone.
不过当他们展示这些东西时
But also when they present these things
这全是关于功能、智能和那些疯狂的AI魔法编辑器
it's all about the features, the smarts, the crazy AI magic editor
还有这些手机上的所有AI技术
and all this AI stuff on these phones.
Pixel体验有很多值得期待的地方
There's a lot to the Pixel experience.
所以说 谷歌是Android的开发者
So, Google makes Android.
谷歌还自己制造Android手机
Google makes their own Android phone.
所以 谷歌安卓手机应该是
Therefore, the Google Android phone should be the vessel
展示安卓最新功能的最佳选择
for showing off the latest and greatest
来自安卓 是吧？
from Android, right?
我说的是 安卓15的预览在二月刚曝光
I mean, Android 15 preview just got shown off in February.
将在年底发布
It's coming out by the end of the year.
这些手机预装安卓14
These phones launch with Android 14.
这可不是开玩笑
That's not a joke.
所有这些Pixel 9都运行安卓的第二最新版本
All these Pixel 9s are running the second latest version of Android
出厂时
out the box.
显然 他们应该是优先获得安卓15的
Obviously, they should be first in line for 15
然后是七年的软件更新承诺
and then the seven years of promised software updates
但这真是太搞笑了
but that's still hilarious.
每次我重新使用 Pixel
But every time I go back to using a Pixel, you know
我想起了用其他手机时错过的功能
I'm reminded of all this stuff that I miss when I use other phones,
比如通话筛选
like call screening.
实在是太好了
So good.
我知道三星的 Bixby 版本有点糟糕
I mean, I know Samsung kind of has like a janky Bixby version of it
可效果比不上 Pixel
but it doesn't work as well.
我尝试过
I've tried.
还有一个现在播放的功能
The now playing feature also
它会在你身边悄悄地告诉你
that just kind of ambiently tells you
正在播放的歌曲
what song is playing in the background
wherever you're at.
我超喜欢这个
Love it.
而且现在他们又增加了很多新功能
And now there's all this new stuff that they're adding
这可能会让人们对Pixel感兴趣
that also may or may not hook people to the Pixel.
所以通话备注是一个新功能
So call notes is a new one.
挺实用的
Pretty useful.
对正在通话进行录音并总结
Summarize the phone calls that you're on with a recording.
新的Pixel天气应用最初我以为不怎么样
And the new Pixel weather app Originally
我原本没打算太看重它 但说实话
I wasn't going to give that much of a chance to it, but honestly
它的表现与我用过的其他
it's turned out to be just as good as basically any other
Android天气应用一样好
Android weather app I've tried.
点击主页上的天气小部件即可使用
So you can get to it by tapping the weather widget on the home screen
界面设计得很漂亮
and it's got this really pretty UI
你可以在这里重新排列大图标
where you can rearrange the big tiles
把你最关心的内容放在前面
and put the ones you care most about closer to the top.
虽然它不允许你更改天气来源 但我想说
It doesn't let you change your weather source, but I mean
我这算是为难
I'm already nitpicking at a level
那些只在意细节的天气爱好者了
that only weather nerds will really care about.
他们还加了新版全景界面和相机功能
And they also threw in an updated panorama UI and the camera.
不过我不知道还有谁会在意这个
And I don't know if anybody cares about this
但Pro版的温度传感器现在可以测量人体温度了
but the temperature sensor in the Pros works on people now.
不知道你有没有注意到这一点
I don't know if you caught that.
而且它现在能提供实时温度读数
And it gives these live temperature readings now
在你环绕物体时
as you move around an object
顺带说明 这些并不算医疗建议
none of which is medical advice, by the way.
我真的是有点佩服谷歌的坚持
I'm actually impressed by Google's commitment
对这个特别无用的应用
to this particularly useless app.
毕竟 谷歌 我知道你们因取消项目而受到批评
Like, Google, I know you get a lot of heat for killing things typically
但我觉得你们可以放弃这个温度计应用
but I give you permission to stop working on the thermometer app, I think.
我觉得你们做到了
I think you've done it.
不过 有一点我想再提一下
But there's one thing that, again
如果你看了谷歌的活动
if you watched Google's event
这正是让Pixel与其他
that is really supposed to stand the pixel out from the rest
智能手机不同之处
of the world of smartphones.
这正是双子星运作的地方
And that is because this is where Gemini lives.
这与谷歌最新助手的整合非常深入
This is this deep, deep integration with Google's newest assistant here.
这款手机的开机动画竟然是谷歌的图标
Literally the boot up animation on this phone is the Google logo.
启动时 它会变成双子座的图标
And then it turns into the Gemini logo before it starts up.
其实这些就是...
Like these are basically...
就是双子座手机
Gemini phones.
那么 让我们聊聊这个
So let's talk about it.
我们先撇开谷歌这种让人困惑的品牌更名惯例不谈
So ignoring the fact that Google has this horrible habit of rebranding
以及那种让人困惑的重新命名方式
and renaming things in the most confusing way possible
显然 我们在这里应该聚焦于双子座
it seems clear that Gemini is the thing we should be focusing on here.
这个小盒子肩负着很大的压力
Like there's a lot of pressure on this little box
必须尽量做到实用
to be as useful as possible.
而且它确实表现不错 我觉得双子助手很实用
And it actually delivers like I have found Gemini to be very useful
而且最近几周它也在迅速改进
and also rapidly improving over the past couple weeks
增加了不少新功能
and gaining new capabilities
它仍然能够很好地进行对话 记得上下文
and it's still it's very conversational remembers context
绝大多数情况下能正确回答问题 表现不错
it gets questions correct most the time it's good
我显然需要更新一下助手的比较
I clearly need to do an updated assistant battle
因为我上次比较的是谷歌助手 而不是双子
because the last one I did was with Google Assistant not Gemini
但这真是奇怪
but see that's the weird thing
谷歌居然向大家推出了这个全新的Gemini助手
Google introduced this huge new Gemini assistant to everyone
而且谷歌助手在这些手机上仍然
but also Google Assistant still exists
和Gemini助手同时存在
alongside Gemini on these phones too.
就好像有两个不同的助手
Like it's two different assistants.
其实 有一段时间
Matter of fact, for a little while
谷歌助手实际上比Gemini更强
Google Assistant was actually better than Gemini at a lot of things
普通人使用的功能
for what regular people were doing with it
因为Gemini助手不能设定定时器
because Gemini couldn't set timers
它不能提供去某个地方的路线
it couldn't get directions to places
它也无法进行基本的家居控制
it couldn't do basic home controls.
因此 谷歌助手将成为人们依赖的工具
And so Google Assistant would be the thing
人们还是会依赖它
that it would fall back on
而且人们也会持续使用
and that people would continue to use.
这让人感到困惑
It's confusing.
即使是现在的Pixel 9
Even now on the Pixel 9
你只需长按电源按钮
you can hold down the power button
或从角落向上滑动 打开Gemini
or swipe up from the corner to get to Gemini.
但每部手机上都有的Pixel主屏幕小部件
But the permanent Pixel home screen widget on everyone's phone
如果你点一下那个麦克风
if you tap that microphone
那就是旧版的谷歌助手了
that's the old Google Assistant.
如今 Gemini实际上可以设置计时器和闹钟
But today, now, Gemini can actually set timers and alarms.
它能够听取背景音乐 告诉你正在播放的是什么歌曲
And it can listen and tell you what song is playing in the background
但之前它是无法做到的
when it couldn't before.
它可以进行智能家居控制 比如调节Nest恒温器的温度
And it can do home controls like changing my Nest thermostat temperature
和开启智能灯
and turning smart lights on.
但不知为何
But for some weird reason
当它具备这些新能力时
when it's doing all of these new capabilities
角落里显示个小Google助手标志
it's showing me a little Google Assistant logo in the corner
仿佛在告诉我 ‘好的’
as if to tell me like, okay
它能正常运作 还有新功能
it works and we have this new capability
不过双子星是依赖旧版Google助手来完成这些功能的
but Gemini is doing this through the old Google Assistant
那这有什么必要告诉我？
which why even tell me that?
直接去做吧
Just do the thing.
总之 在设置里也有这些功能
So anyway, then also in the settings
你可以使用这些双子星扩展
you'll be able to have these Gemini extensions
启用后
which when you enable them
这将使双子星更深入了解你的生活 通过其他应用
will let Gemini see more into your actual life, like through other apps
例如Google文档、Google云端硬盘和日历
like Google Docs and Drive and your calendar.
对我而言 这才是最有用的地方
And to me, that's really where it becomes the most useful.
我开始请求它帮我找邮件
Like I start asking it to find emails for me
告诉我下一个日历事件的交通情况
and tell me the traffic to my next calendar event and things like that.
这就像跟一个普通人在交流 特别实用
That is just like talking to a normal person and it's super useful.
不过 Gemini Live 有时会让人感觉不太舒适
But then Gemini Live gets into this slightly less comfortable sometimes,
但也时常非常有用
but also sometimes very useful.
可以跟Gemini进行完全交谈
fully conversational mode with Gemini.
所以你就这么打开它 它就会全屏了
So you just open it like this and it's full screen.
好吧 我的工作室里有个黄蜂巢
So, okay, I've got this wasp nest in my studio
我得把它处理掉
and I need to get rid of it.
我该怎么做？
What do I do?
黄蜂比较凶猛
Wasps are pretty aggressive,
因此安全清除蜂巢是重中之重
so getting rid of the nest safely is the priority.
你知道蜂巢里是哪种黄蜂吗？
Do you know what kind of wasps are in the nest?
这样我就能找到帮你清除它的最好方法
That will help me figure out the best way to help you remove it.
我完全没主意
I have no idea
不过它们总是活跃得很
but they're all really active all the time.
好吧 这说得通
Okay, that makes sense.
首先 最好试着
To start, it's best to try
弄清楚你遇到的是什么种类的黄蜂
and figure out what kind of wasps you're dealing with.
它们是黄黑相间、腰身细长的吗？
Are they yellow and black with a narrow waist?
如果是这样 那它们可能是黄蜂
If so, they're probably yellow jackets.
还是它们更像棕色的？
Or are they more brown
还是灰色的 腰部更宽一些？
or gray with a wider waist?
那它们是纸巢蜂
Those would be paper wasps.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我可不想跟它们靠这么近
I don't want to get that close to them.
我还是去找附近的灭虫服务吧？
How about I just find pest control nearby?
你能帮我搞定吗？
Can you do that?
好的 那就这样
Okay.
所以这一切都得看你的网络好不好了
So this is all at the mercy of your internet connection.
而且不能出错 保持信息完整
and it not hallucinating and getting everything right.
不过一旦它实现
But when it does, it's actually
那确实会非常有用
it can be super useful
特别是当你有很多
especially when you have like a bunch of
后续问题时
follow-up questions about something
你就会想继续深入
and you want to just keep going
这样就不需要在谷歌上打字 只需直接说话即可
then it's less of a bunch of typing Google and just talking to it.
没问题
It's fine.
所以我觉得 Gemini现在真的做得不错
So I do think Gemini is actually really good at this point.
当然 我打算与新Siri进行比较
I will plan on doing a comparison to the new Siri, of course
也会对比ChatGPT和其他一些助手
probably ChatGPT and probably some others
欢迎大家订阅！
in some Updated assistant battle feel free to get subscribed
如果你想等它发布 那就得等等了
if you want to see that when it comes out, but as of right now
是的 我很喜欢Gemini助手的功能
Yeah, I'm I'm a fan of what assistant assistant of what Gemini is doing
但实际上 使用Gemini你可以在任何安卓手机上完成这些功能
but the thing is you can do any of this with Gemini on any android phone
实际上 谷歌用Galaxy S24 Ultra演示了Gemini
matter of fact google literally demoed gemini with the galaxy s24 ultra
在自己的活动中
at their own event
就连他们都没打算掩饰这一点
like they didn't even try to hide it
那么如果这并不是Pixel独有的
so if that's not unique to pixel
那么如果这就是Gemini手机
and it's basically the gemini phone
那新NPU的强大又有什么意义呢
like what's the point of all this new npu power
搭配Tensor G4
with the tensor g4
这些额外用于人工智能的内存究竟有什么用呢？
and all this extra ram dedicated to ai tasks what exactly is that good for
其实还有不少其他的人工智能任务
well there are a bunch of other ai tasks
所以我打算这样来分析这些功能
So here's how I want to go through these.
Pixel 9有许多新推出的人工智能功能
There's a bunch of new AI features on the Pixel 9s
我想把它们分成有用的、一般的和噱头设计
and I want to just sort of divide them into useful, meh, and gimmicks
这是我这段时间使用它们的亲身体验
based on my own experience with them over the past couple weeks.
我都尝试了一下这些功能
I've been trying them all, using them
对它们做了全面的测试
putting through their paces
我有一些看法
and I have some thoughts.
所以其中一些功能确实相当不错
So some of them are really good
这增强了Pixel的使用体验 还有其他优点...
and add to the Pixel experience, and others...
其实并没那么好 有点被高估了
Not that great, kind of overrated.
总的来说 在实用性上 我觉得Gemini还是有用的 毕竟它只是一个助手
So under useful, I'm putting Gemini, of course, just the assistant overall.
反应很快 处理得也不错 整体不错
It's quick, it gets things right, fine.
接下来是通话记录、视频增强功能 还有‘加我’的选项
Then I have call notes, video boost, and add me.
视频增强似乎在画质上确实带来了意想不到的变化
So video boost actually seems to make a surprising difference at
视频质量真是不错
how good the video quality comes out of a pixel
你能从这些功能中获得的体验也很丰富
and what you can get out of these.
通话记录功能很方便
call notes is is convenient
因为如果你敢在通话中启用这个功能
because if you have the guts to turn it on on a phone call
它可以记录所有内容并进行转录和总结
it can record everything in just at all transcribe it summarize it
而且通话结束后会把内容发送给你
and give you that after the phone call
这功能真是太实用了
which is it's just useful
然后加我一下 哈哈 这听起来很有趣 很不错
and then add me haha had me add me is interesting it's good
它的效果不错
It works pretty well.
我只是觉得
I just
我不太确定人们是否会真正使用它
I'm not sure if people are going to actually use it
或者他们只是试一次就不再用了
or if they're going to like try it once
然后就把它忘了
and then forget about it
然后再回去拍自拍
and go back to taking selfies.
但它好用 能正常发挥功能
But it does what it's supposed to.
就在那个人像模式旁边
It's right there next to the portrait mode.
使用相机时很容易找到
It's easy to access in the camera.
如果你需要拍团体照
And so if you need to take a group shot
而你又没有人帮你拍
and you actually have no one to take it for you
这个功能真的很实用
this feature is genuinely useful.
它只需合并两张照片 哇
It just combines two pictures and boom
现在所有人都在照片里了
everyone's now on the photo.
你可能在想 没错
In case you were wondering, yes
你可以和自己一起拍照
you can do add me with yourself.
是的 如果你仔细看像素细节
And yes, if you pixel peep
你会发现它并不是每次都完美
you can tell that it's not perfect every single time.
边缘有些模糊
There are fuzzy edges.
显然是用了第一张照片的基本框架
It's clearly using the base frame from the first photo
然后再合成最后一个人
and then compositing in the last person.
不过 总体来说 谷歌做得这么深入
But in general, the fact that Google has leaned this far in
还凭空创造了一个非常实用的功能
and created a genuinely useful feature out of thin air
简直抛弃了现实
by just abandoning reality
在 Pixel 相机应用里 我想是这样的
in the Pixel camera app I guess, yeah
你得给他们点个赞啊
you gotta give them credit.
但人们真的知道怎么用这个吗？
It's just will people actually know to use this
他们会往常一样拍自拍吗？
or will they just go back to taking like a selfie with everyone behind them
这样就能把每个人都拍进来？
so they get everyone in the shot?
我也不太清楚
I don't know.
时间会告诉我们
Only time will tell.
所以那个就有点无聊了
So then there's meh.
还有些还不错的东西
There's like the okay stuff.
在新的天气应用里 我能看到新的天气摘要
So I have the new weather summaries in the new weather app.
这些是人工智能生成的
They're AI generated.
在应用的最上方
So right at the top of the app there
上面会给你介绍今天的情况
it gives you some text to describe the day for you
这样你就不用看那些烦人的数字了
so you don't have to look at all those confusing numbers underneath.
老实说 这有时候还挺有用的
Honestly, it's actually kind of useful sometimes.
不过这真的是人工智能吗？
But is this really AI?
也许这个句子的结构是来自某种语言模型？
Like, maybe the sentence structure is coming from an LLM or something?
我不知道
I don't know.
无所谓
Whatever.
没问题
It's fine.
它肯定没跟我说这些云要来了
It certainly didn't tell me about all this clouds coming in,
可能还会下雨
probably gonna dump some rain
还会影响我的光线
and also ruin my lighting.
但魔法编辑器推出了一个新功能
But then Magic Editor got this re-imagine feature
可以让你突出图像的任意部分
that lets you highlight any part of an image
然后输入一些文本 让你的照片焕然一新
and then enter some text to turn it into something else
completely different to have your photos look like
我也不太清楚
I don't know
一个幻想世界 没发生过的事情
a fantasy land or something that also never happened.
它就是不愿意处理我那些更戏剧化的编辑
It does outright refuse to do some of my more dramatic edits.
就像 它好像从来不想重新想象人物
Like, it doesn't seem to want to reimagine people ever.
但是 它会高兴地给背景加一些物体
But it'll happily add objects to the background
或者 还能改变场景
or change the setting entirely if you're into that.
这我就不知道了
I don't know.
照片到底算什么呢？
What is a photo anyway?
最后一个 虽然也没什么特别的
And then the last meh, but not least, or whatever
这是截图应用
is the Screenshots app.
我是不是漏掉了什么？
am i missing something here
我的意思是 我明白这个前提
i mean i get the premise
你手机里有一些截图
you have some screenshots on your phone that you've taken
为了保存一些重要信息
where you want to save some critical information in them
他们设计了一个存储空间
so they built a place
你可以把这些截图整理成不同的集合
where you can organize them all into collections
这非常方便 你可以搜索
which is convenient you can search through them
还可以设置特定日期提醒
you can have it remind you at a certain date
以及特定截图的时间
and time of a specific screenshot
甚至可以直接链接到截图的网页
and even link you back to the web page that you took a screenshot of
这使得所有信息都能被搜索
and it makes all this information searchable.
不过 我在想...
But I'm sitting here thinking
难道这不应该已经在谷歌照片里集成了吗？
shouldn't this have been built into Google Photos?
你知道吗 三星的照片应用其实已经实现了
Like, did you know that Samsung's Photos app already built in
智能链接
the smart linking
可以链接到任何你截图的网站
to any website you take a screenshot of?
我是说 别搞错了
I mean, don't get me wrong.
它是有效的
It works.
它做到了该做的事
It does what it's supposed to.
我猜
My theory is it's
他们可能对每张照片中的文本和信息进行了更多分析
they're probably doing slightly more analysis, more processing
对每张照片的文本和信息进行了处理
of all the bits of text and information in each photo.
比起普通的 Google Photos 应用 他们的表现更佳
than they would with the normal Google Photos app.
这正是使所有索引和功能得以实现的原因
So that is what enables all the indexing and everything.
如果一切顺利的话
And then maybe if it goes well
他们是不是也会把这些添加到照片应用里呢？
they'll also bring all that to the Photos app, maybe?
要是进展不顺利的话
Or if it doesn't go well
他们是不是可以轻松放弃呢？
then they can kill it easily?
我不太确定
I don't know.
没事 随便吧
Whatever.
没事 挺好的
It's fine.
不过比起我那一段的花招 这还算不错
That's not, though, as bad as my gimmicks section.
放大增强 真的来了……
So Zoom Enhance...
你听说了吗？
Have you heard about this?
照片应用终于推出了新编辑功能！
There's a new edit feature finally shipping in the Photos app
鼓励你尽情放大照片
that encourages you to zoom all the way in on a photo
然后就可以体验它的像素处理效果
and then let it do its pixel magic
它会播放一段动画 仿佛
where it plays this whole animation like it's going to
要重现你的照片
reconstruct your photo
并揭露隐藏的细节
and find some hidden details.
但它其实并没做到
But it kind of never does.
说到底
At the end of the day
它只是稍微提高了清晰度滤镜
all it does is sort of turn up the clarity filter
可能还加了一些假纹理效果
and maybe add what feels like some fake texture
我觉得这里应该有些东西
where I think there should have been some.
我不太信这个
I'm not buying it.
然后是 Pixel Studio 应用
And then there's the Pixel Studio app
这只是一个小而实用的应用
which is just this neat little app
可以在设备上生成新图像
to generate new images completely on device.
我并不是说它不起作用
And again, what I'm not saying is that it doesn't work.
它在设备上大约三秒就能很好地工作
It actually does work impressively well in like three seconds on device.
它可以生成你想要的任何内容
It can generate whatever you want.
我只是觉得
It's just that I don't
我真看不出这有什么实际用途 除了
I guess I don't really see a real genuine use for this other than just
随便玩玩
messing around,
老实说
which, hey, honestly
这样也没问题
that's fine too.
如果你只是想随意玩玩
If you just want to mess around
或者做个带腿的肉丸三明治
and make a meatball sub with legs
那就行 尽情享受吧！
then you got it, knock yourself out.
所以在大雨之前
So before it starts pouring rain
2024年新智能手机的趋势是
the meta with new smartphones in 2024 is, you know,
整体上有些小改进
slight improvements across the board,
而且还推出了一些炫目的新人工智能功能
but then also some splashy new AI features
只在最新款中可用
that are only available on the newest one
这是因为新芯片和神经核心的原因
because the new chip and the new neural cores
因此 这就是它特别的原因
and it's just special for that reason.
所以 这就是现在的情况
So that's, that's what's happening.
如果你愿意的话
And if you want
你可以轻松把这些新Pixel手机视为那种选择
you could easily throw these new Pixels into that camp.
不过 买这款手机的理由其实和以前的
But the reason you'd buy this phone is really just the same
Pixel一样
as ever for a Pixel.
它是房间里最智能的手机
It's the smartest smartphone in the room
而且现在它采用了相当不错的硬件
and it's now also in a piece of kind of nice hardware
使用起来手感都很舒适
that's a pleasure to hold and use.
此外 还有一堆AI功能
And then there's a bunch of AI stuff on top
试试 要么喜欢就用 要么不管它
that you can try and either take it or leave it.
这就看你自己了
It's kind of just up to you
如果你想好好利用这些功能的话
if you want to get a bunch of use out of that stuff
或者连碰都不碰
or literally never touch it at all.
我很好奇你在下面留言
I'm curious if you leave a comment down below
你觉得哪些东西会用得上？
what sort of stuff you think you would use
还是直接买手机使用？
or buy the phone to use
或者你觉得哪些东西根本没用
or which stuff you don't think is that useful at all.
最终来说
At the end of the day
我们还得看看它的耐用性
we'll have to see how it ages
不过我觉得 Pixel 9
but I'm thinking Pixel 9
而 9 Pro 也是他们迄今为止最出色的作品之一
and 9 Pro is some of their finest work yet.
另外 特别感谢 Anker 的赞助
Also, shout out to Anker for sponsoring this video.
他们的新 Anker Prime 系列
Their new Anker Prime lineup
是迄今为止最先进的多设备快充产品
is their most advanced multi-device fast charger they've made yet.
其中包括三个充电站、一个底座、
That includes three charging stations, one docking station,
和一个壁充
one wall charger,
一个移动电源和一根新充电线
one power bank, and one new cable.
对我来说 最突出的两个产品是
So the two that stand out to me the most are
Anker Prime充电站
the Anker Prime charging station
还有Anker Prime移动电源
and the Anker Prime power bank.
这款充电站是一款桌面配件
The charging station is this desktop accessory
总功率可达250瓦
that can kick out 250 watts in total
在四个USB-C和两个USB-A端口中
among its four USB-C and two USB-A ports.
并且配有显示屏
And then it has a display
可以显示每个端口的实时功率
that can show you how much power each port is drawing actively.
而且你可以为每个端口自定义充电优先级
And then it lets you customize charging priority on each port.
因此你可以让它智能地自动调整
So you can let it just sort of auto adjust
让需求最高的设备获得它们能接受的最大充电
and make the highest demanding items get the max charge that they can take.
这个移动电源
And then the power bank
它的容量为9600毫安时 还有两个USB-C端口
has a 9,600 mAh capacity and there's two USB-C ports on it
输出功率最高可达65瓦
and up to 65 watts output from this thing.
而且它也可以当作墙壁充电器使用
But it can also be a wall charger too.
这块1.3英寸的显示屏会显示
So that 1.3 inch display is going to show you
你剩下的电量
how much battery you have left
以及每个端口输出了多少电量
and how much power each of those ports is outputting.
你可以去了解一下它们
So you can check them out
还有其他Anker Prime产品的详细信息 可以在视频描述中查看
and the rest of the Anker Prime lineup in the video description.
反正 这就是我想说的全部
But either way, that's been it.
在下大雨之前 我把这个给做完了
I got this in before.
大雨突然开始了
The pouring rain started
所以我对此还是挺自豪的
so I'm pretty proud of that.
欢迎在下面的评论中告诉我你的想法！
But let me know what you think in the comments below.
下次视频再见！
Talk to you guys in the next one.
拜拜！
Peace.